Junheng Hao

CONTACT INFORMATION Microsoft Azure Cognitive Services Research

E-mail: junhenghao@microsoft.com Mobile: +1 (424)355-5950

Office: Microsoft Bravern-2 Building, 11025 NE 8th St,

Bellevue, WA 98004

DBLP Profile Oct 2022 - Current

CURRENT EMPLOYMENT Researcher, Microsoft

Homepage

Google Scholar

Semantic Scholar

LinkedIn

Knowledge and Language Team at Microsoft Azure Cognitive Services Research Group

RESEARCH **INTERESTS** Knowledge is power; knowledge graphs (KGs) are power to next-generation AI analytics. My research interests lie at the intersection of graph learning, data mining, natural language processing and machine learning with a focus on knowledge graphs, especially learning symbolic and semantic structures inside KGs and multimodal AI.

EDUCATION

University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), CA, USA

Sept 2022

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Thesis: Incorporating ontological information in knowledge graph learning and applications

Advisors: Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang

Tsinghua University, Beijing, China

May 2017

B. Eng. in School of Information Science and Technology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (INDUSTRY)

Research Intern at Microsoft Research (MSR), Redmond, WA

June 2021 - Sept 2021

• Mentors: Chieh-Han Wu, Zhihong (Iris) Shen, Ye-Yi Wang, Jennifer Neville

PhD Research Intern at IBM Research AI, San Jose, CA

June 2020 - Sept 2020

• Mentor: Chuan Lei, Berthold Reinwald, Fatma Ozcan

Applied Scientist Intern/Student Researcher at Amazon, Seattle, WA June 2019 - Dec 2019

• Mentors: Tong Zhao, Luna Xin Dong, Christos Faloutsos

Research Intern at **NEC Lab America**, Princeton, NJ

June 2018 - Sept 2018

• Mentors: Lu-An Tang, Zhichun Li, Haifeng Chen

PUBLICATION SUMMARY

As of October 2022: I have accomplished 10+ Papers published papers and submissions (260+ citations), among which I first-authored papers published on top-tier venues (KDD, CIKM, BCB) from interdisciplinary domains across NLP, recommendation and bioinformatics. More up-to-date publications can be found in *Google Scholar*. Several research works and internship projects (such as P-Companion [2]) have been successfully deployed in market-scale product.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS & **SUBMISSIONS**

- [1] Multi-source Inductive Graph Knowledge Transfer Junheng Hao, Lu-An Tang, Yizhou Sun, Zhengzhang Chen, Haifeng Chen, Junghwan Rhee, Zhichun Li and Wei Wang. Proceedings of Joint European Conference on Machine Learning and Knowledge Discovery in Databases (ECML-PKDD). September 2022.
- [2] Metadata-Induced Contrastive Learning for Zero-Shot Multi-Label Text Classification Yu Zhang, Zhihong Shen, Chieh-Han Wu, Boya Xie, Junheng Hao, Ye-Yi Wang, Kuansan Wang and Jiawei Han. Proceedings of The Web Conference (WWW) 2022. April 2022.
- [3] MEDTO: Medical Data to Ontology Matching using Hybrid Graph Neural Networks Junheng Hao, Chuan Lei, Abdul Quamar, Vasilis Efthymiou, Fatma Ozcan, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Proceedings of 27th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD, Applied Data Science Track). August 2021.

- [4] *P-Companion: Framework for Diversified Complementary Product Recommendation* **Junheng Hao**, Tong Zhao, Jin Li, Luna Xin Dong, Christos Faloutsos, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Proceedings of the 29th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), Applied Research Track. October 2020. [Amazon Blog]
- [5] Bio-JOIE: Joint Representation Learning of Biological Knowledge Bases

 Junheng Hao, Chelsea J.-T. Ju, Muhao Chen, Yizhou Sun, Carlo Zaniolo, Wei Wang.

 Proceedings of The 11th ACM Conference on Bioinformatics, Computational Biology, and
 Health Informatics (ACM BCB 2020), September 2020. Best Student Paper Award.
- [6] Universal Representation Learning of Knowledge Bases by Jointly Embedding Instances and Ontological Concepts Junheng Hao, Muhao Chen, Wenchao Yu, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Proceedings of 25th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD, Research Track). August 2019.
- [7] EHIA: Empowering Homicide Analytics with MurderBook Knowledge Graphs and Domainspecific Language Models Junheng Hao, Jingyue Shen, Craig D. Uchida, Yizhou Sun, P. Jeffrey Brantingham, Wei Wang. Preprint, under review.
- [8] KG-Doc: Hybrid Knowledge Graph Infused Document Representation Learning **Junheng Hao**, Chieh-Han Wu, Zhihong Shen, Boya Xie, Jennifer Neville, Ye-Yi Wang, Yizhou Sun, Wei Wang. Preprint.

PATENT APPLICATIONS

[9] OntoGNN: Hybrid Graph Neural Networks for Ontology Matching. Chuan Lei, Junheng Hao, Vasilis Efthymiou, Fatma Ozcan, Abdul Quamar. U.S. Patent Application (Sept. 2021)

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Conference Program Committee & Reviewer: NeurIPS, KDD, ICML, AAAI, WWW, ICLR, IJCAI, EMNLP, ACL Rolling Review, ICDE, SDM, WSDM, ECML-PKDD, CIKM.
- Journal Reviewer: TPAMI, TBD, TIST, TKDD
- Conference Volunteer: ICLR, KDD, EMNLP, NeurIPS.

INVITED TALKS

- Dec 2021: Coupang, Ranking, Discovery and Personalization. Invited tech talk: *Knowledge Graphs Meets Product Recommendation: One Deep Learning Solution*.
- Aug 2021: Microsoft Search, Assistant and Intelligence (MSAI). Graph learning session: *Knowledge Graph with Ontology Learning and Applications*.
- July 2019: Amazon, Product Graph. Invited talk: Representation Learning on Knowledge Graphs: Embedding, Logic Rules and Graph Neural Networks (with Yizhou Sun).

Honors and Awards

• Best Student Paper Award (ACM BCB)

2020

• NAACL D&I Subsidy Award, ACL DEI Grant

2022

• SIGIR Student Travel Grant (CIKM)

2020, 2021

• Student Travel Award (KDD)

2019, 2020

TEACHING

- CSM146: Introduction to Machine Learning (Winter 2021)
- CS145: Introduction to Data Mining (Fall 2020, Fall 2018)
- CS32: Introduction to Computer Science II, Data Structures (Spring 2019, Winter 2019)

SKILLS

- Programming: Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow), C/C++, LATEX, MATLAB, SQL
- Language: Mandarin (Native), English (Proficient), Spanish (Basic)